Jonathan B. Conger

jbconger@gmail.com = linkedin.com/in/jbconger = 435 890-4950

Passionate software engineer and game designer with experience in gameplay systems and design. Strong technical communicator proficient in research and documentation. Diverse background in management, production, finance, physical science, and political science.

SKILLS

Development

- Skilled in object-oriented programming, data structures, algorithms, software practice, and design patterns
- Proficient in Visual Studio 2019/Code, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, and other proprietary tools
- Create code framework and document research for new audio system in NBA2K23
- Versed in C++, C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Design

- Contribute to multi-discipline teams focused on player experience, seasonal rewards, and game progression
- Collaborate with various teams in iterative prototyping using digital and paper-based mediums
- Design gameplay, user experience, and levels for several game projects

Team and Project Management

- Direct teams of up to 9 members focusing on game development, marketing, and design
- Advise clients on more than 50 branding, marketing, event, and development projects
- Manage client service teams including web services, product support, and billing for over 300 clients
- Skilled in Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Office, and other project management tools

GAME PROJECTS

NBA2K23 – sports (basketball)

May 2022 - Aug 2022

Role: Live Ops Engineer

- Work with engineering, design, production, and art teams to develop and improve game systems
- Investigate and document audio playback options using proprietary code and tools, bug fixes, playtesting

Rapid Prototyping Series – various genres

Fall 2021 – Spring 2022

Role: Game Engineer, Gameplay Designer, Producer

Develop a variety of games using various tools MonoGame, Phaser 3, Unreal, and Unity

Unity Projects: Airrow, True Blue – twin-stick shooter, 2D platformer

Fall 2019 - Spring 2020

Role: Gameplay Engineer, Level Designer

• Design and develop gameplay systems, levels, and user experience using Unity and Corgi Engine

EDUCATION

Master of Entertainment Arts and Engineering (MEAE) – University of Utah	May 2023
BS Computer Science, Game Engineering (52 credit hours completed) - University of Utah	Dec 2020
BS Economics, BS Human Biology, Chemistry Minor - Utah State University	Dec 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Developer	University of Utah GSLC	Oct 2018 – Present
Software Engineer Intern	Visual Concepts Austin	May 2022 – Aug 2022
Admin. Assistant/Accountant	University of Utah HSC Core Research	Sep 2017 – Oct 2018
Committee on Finance Intern	United States Senate	Jan 2017 – May 2017
PR and Marketing Assist. Director	USU Student Association	Jan 2016 – Dec 2016